Finding Aid for Mack & Company records, 1858-1940
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Mack & Company records
1858-1940
Mack & Company (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
85477 Bb.2 2; BB.2 Out. Vol.
Ann Arbor, Michigan, dry goods store. Ledgers, cash books, payroll books, sales books, and photographs; also records, 1902-1913, of the estate of Christian Mack, and records, 1874-1922, of the Mack Insurance Agency.
4.5 linear feet
12 microfilms
5 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was the gift of Christian Mack (donor no. 1921 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
Founded in 1860 by Christian Mack, Mack & Company was at one time Ann Arbor's largest department store. In addition to the sale of clothing and household merchandise, the company would come to offer other services as well, including an insurance agency, a bank, and the leasing of properties owned by family members to other businesses. In 1939, because of declining sales, the store closed.
The records of Mack & Company include the following kinds of business records: Financial ledgers; Mack insurance agency records; bank depositor records; various sales, payroll, and financial record books; and miscellaneous tax materials; investment files; employee material; and store publications.
Subjects:
General stores--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Insurance--Michigan.; Mack, Christian, 1834-1902.; Mack Insurance Agency (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
- Ledgers (Microfilm)
  - 1858-1863 (Box 5, Reel 1)
  - 1901-1903 (Box 5, Reel 1)
  - 1906-1908 (Box 5, Reel 2)
  - 1909-1914 (Box 5, Reel 3)
    (A-D)
  - 1909-1914 (Box 5, Reel 4)
    (E-R)
  - 1909-1914 (Box 5, Reel 5)
    (S-Z)
  - 1914-1917 (Box 5, Reel 5)
  - 1914-1917 (Box 5, Reel 6)
    (E-K)
  - 1914-1917 (Box 5, Reel 7)
    (L-Z)
  - 1917-1919 (Box 5, Reel 8)
    (A-K)
  - 1917-1919 (Box 5, Reel 9)
  - 1901-1903 (Box 1)
    (M&S ledger; fragmentary)
  - Indexes to ledgers, 9 volumes (Box 1)
  - Indexes to ledgers, 10 volumes (Box 2)
- Insurance Agency
  - Ledgers
    - 1922-1923 (Box 3)
    - 1924-1925 (Box 3)
  - Letterpress book of the Christian Mack Insurance Agency, 1902-1907 (Box 3)
  - Record of expirations of insurance policies for the Christian Mack Agency, 1874-1920 (Box 3)
  - Sales Record
    - 1881-1890 (Volume 1)
    - 1890-1897 (Volume 2)
  - Policy Record, 1922-1925 (Volume 3)
- Other records
  - Records of the Mack and Company Savings Bank, circa 1904-1936 (Box 3)
  - Cash/Order Book, 1901-1904 (Box 5, Reel 10)
  - Insurance Accounts, 1908-1916 (Box 5, Reel 10)
  - Insurance Accounts, 1916-1922 (Box 5, Reel 11)
  - Time and Payroll Book, 1909-1910 (Box 5, Reel 11)
  - Time and Payroll Book, 1912-1913 (Box 5, Reel 11)
  - Sales Book, 1875-1881 (Box 5, Reel 11)
  - Sales Books, 1900-1919 (Box 5, Reel 12)
  - Cash Book, 1859-1866 (Volume 4)
  - Scrapbook of sales brochures of Mack and Company, 1926-1928 (Volume 5)
  - Cash Book of the estate of Christian Mack, 1902-1910 (Box 4)
  - Departmental record book, 1901-1914 (Box 4)
  - Walter C. Mack record book, 1889-1897 (Box 4)
  - Cash Book, 1901-1906 (Box 4)
  - Annual and Semi-annual financial statements, 1892-1901 (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous Papers records:
  (tax materials, other investments, employee material, and publications)
  - Balance Sheets, 1889-1892 (Box 4)
  - Record of Hosiery Sales, 1936-1938 (Box 4)
  - Record of Sales of the Cunningham Drug Store, 1936-1938 (Box 4)
  - Papers concerning the estate of Christian Mack, 1908-1913 (Box 4)
  - Receipt, 1862 (Box 4)
  - Papers concerning annual meetings of stockholders, 1895-1939 (Box 4)
  - Retail Stores of Ann Arbor income tax returns.
    - 1931-1933 (Box 4)
    - 1934-1935 (Box 4)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 4)
  - Mack and Company and Mercantile Properties (operation income tax returns)
    - 1932 (Box 4)
    - 1933-1934 (Box 4)
  - Mercantile Properties Corporation income tax returns, 1934-1937 (Box 4)
  - Mack and Company income tax returns
    - 1934-1935 (Box 4)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 4)
  - Income tax papers concerning employees, 1930-1938 (Box 4)
  - Income tax returns of Walter C. Mack, 1932-1937 (Box 4)
  - Income tax returns of Christian Mack, 1936-1937 (Box 4)
  - Income tax returns of Virginia Mack, 1936 (Box 4)
  - Income tax return of W.C. Mack, 1940 (Box 4)
  - Mack and Company Statements
    - 1919-1923 (Box 4)
    - 1924-1929 (Box 4)
    - 1930-1936 (Box 4)
  - Retail Stores of Ann Arbor (Box 4)
  - Mercantile Properties Corporation (Box 4)
  - W.C. Mack Realty Company (Box 5)
  - Mack and Company balance sheets, 1923-1935 (Box 5)
  - Mack and Company dividend records (Box 5)
  - Diagrams of the Mack and Company building, 1924; 1927 (Box 5)
  - Loan from the University of Michigan, 1935-1940 (Box 5)
  - Cunningham Drug Store lease (Box 5)
  - Robin Redbreast Hosiery Company lease (Box 5)
  - Pansy Hosiery Company lease (Box 5)
  - Schwaebischer Unterstuetzungs Verein lease (Box 5)
  - Vogel lease (Box 5)
  - Book of Rules for employees of Mack and Company (Box 5)
  - Lewis G. Christman's work as trustee for Mack and Company, 1939-1940 (Box 5)
  - Walter Mack's purchase of stock in the Hoover Steel Ball Company (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Newsletter -- The Mackazine (Box 5)
  - Memos to Employees (Box 5)
  - Lists of Employees, 1913-1924 (Box 5)
  - Microfilm (Box 5)
    (positive use copy; contents described above)